Vanessa Azenwa Shiundu

+254717400821 | vanessa.azenwa@gmail.com | Nairobi, Kenya

Summary

Title: Fullstack Software Developer

I am a talented Junior Software Engineer trained to work with customers, team members and project leaders to accomplish software engineering and updating tasks according to timelines.

With a solid understanding of full development lifecycle, skilled to work with front and back-end technologies to produce and evaluate projects, I look forward to joining a dynamic team and contribute towards providing creative solutions and making the world a better place; one day at a time.

In addition, I have industry specific training and experience in IT, Statistics and Finance. View My LinkedIn Profile, My GitHub Profile and my Portfolio for a glimpse of some applications and websites I have built over this year.

Skills

Django, Flask, Python, Flutter, WordPress, Angular, React, Google Cloud Platform, CSS3, JavaScript, APIs, Git, Databases, PostgreSQL

Education

Moringa School | Nairobi Software Engineering | 07/2022

ACCA

Diploma in Business and Accounting | 10/2016

Google and Livity Africa
Digital Marketing | 06/2015

Alliance Française de Nairobi DIploma in French | 11/2014

University of Nairobi Statistics and Statistical Packages | 10/2013

St. Theresea's Eregi Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education | 11/2011 A-

St. Teresa's Isanjiro Kenya Certificate of Primary Education | 11/2007 A

Experience

Greenspoon Kenya Itd | Nairobi, Nairobi County Developer - Intern | 10/2022 - Present

- Responsible for both back-end and front-end development of the organization's existing website including the
 implementation of WordPress plugins and custom functionality. This is as required by internal and external stakeholders.
- Monitoring website availability and performing regular maintenance / upgrades on WordPress plugins and core.
- · Conducting website performance tests
- Troubleshooting issues
- Performing regular plugin, theme and core updates and resolving issues in Staging environment before transferring changes to Live
- · Train internal teams as required

Proactively monitoring website performance and availability and suggesting solutions to improve speed, performance & optimizations

Software Developer | 01/2022 - Present

- Efficient collaboration with team members and leading a number of projects as SCRUM MASTER.
- · Designing the structure of websites and apps, optimizing for mobile devices
- Creating the logic that instructs applications on how to interpret user input and what feedback to give the user after
 executing the submitted request I achieved this by creating algorithms that fetch and manipulate data stored in database
 systems mainly using python, Flask, Django, Flutter and SQL.
- Developing app integration with REST APIs for google maps, social media authentication, movie APIs and other services.
- · Proficient in Git and Git-hub for version control
- Managing time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades
- · Planning, writing and debugging web applications and software with complete accuracy.

Nairobi East SDA Church Reliever Church Accountant | 11/2021 - 12/2021

Vivo Energy Kenya Finance Assistant | 03/2019 - 03/2020

Engen Kenya Itd Intern cum Retail Stations Assistant | 04/2017 - 02/2019

Languages

English, French, Swahili

References

1. Aleeda Fazal,

CTO - Chief Technology Officer,

Greenspoon Kenya Itd

2. Stanley Njuru,

Treasurer,

Vivo Energy Kenya Itd.

3. Philip Migire,

Treasurer - Nairobi East SDA,

Contact details available upon request